Now, let's learn about cruise algorithm and how to implement it in sea language.
We start by including the studio and defining the max, certainly.
And we start by defining type, define structure and use structure called edge.
And we start by defining and u v w.
And this is that they've defined the edge lest we create an array of edge at that data and having the
max as its length.
And we specify that we create an edge list e list and like you think about that and if you are using
Java as an object of it, but this is the reference and say No, we have created the list.
Remember it.
We are going to create a graph.
As I told you, the graph is a 2D array having maximum as a length.
And J.
And like, they're like columns and rows and columns.
Length and the edge list called Span List.
Create also a structure of this essentialist.
Let's learn about the algorithm itself.
We create a method called void cruise called Algo, call it, and we start by making end to find this
out of the calling of these methods.
No, the void cruise algorithm applying cruise we create belongs array with length.
Max, I.
J.
S.A. one and scenario two.
We will see these variables how to use each list at the end and equal to zero.
We call it and we seven.
Now we make a for loop a nested for loop with AI and G elements.
And we check if that graph at index and does not equal to zero, then enlist the data at index released
and that you equal to zero and the three equal to G.
And W equal to at the end, and we will see that you we have seen this the end, you V and W that element
that vertex and their way.
We increase and we know we need to call the method, sir.
So for that, we've called for an equal to zero I less than an hour plus plus we think we put and we
insulated belongs at index are equal to index is equal to I know for equal to zero I less than he listed
and we need to and I plus plus we need to go through all the animals from the or two to a list.
Then we are accessing the elements.
We are calling CNO and we are and like initializing and assigning the variables, you know, by the
result of the find a method that we are going to implement.
And in next couple of minutes, I say no to also the result of fine, but the first one is passing you.
And the second one is by saying that if CNO one does not equal, say no to then spend less data and
make this thing and applying that union.
This is very important.
The lungs send one and C.A..
Let's move and learn about that variable.
The methods that we have created and we have used in the previous so and find stuff by belongs and the
vertex number.
If it this belongs, then it will return the lungs at index vertex at and this separate returning index
if it is belong.
So we will see the balloon and apply union.
This is the method that we have created.
And we have used it before, so apply union here.
We create a for loop I from AI, from AI equal to zero to Islas then and increase AI by one and go through
all the elements.
And let's check if belongs at the index equal to see to them belongs at the index equal to one.
Now sorting the algorithm, we have used also this sort of method here.
Where is or she goes, he is.
In this sort here.
Etched stamp.
We start by sorting this algorithm.
We have learned about this sorting algorithm in the previous videos, so please go back to the sorting
algorithms in order to learn about the sorting.
It says we are checking if the if the next variable is less than it, how to sort the array by using
that sorting algorithm, printing the result, it's very simple by using that, by using our loop that
a check and print all this data.
Now.
In order to test our program, we need to go to the main and we air, we create A.J. and total cost.
And we start by an equal to six and graf at index.
I is at row zero and column zero is equal to zero and these are their other elements of their match.
So I need from you to write this and see in the compiler how it works.
And also, I want from you to draw a graph on paint or one note and see what is the result of the final
graph.
Like this if you are going to move from this, from this?
So what is there these numbers and how to make this connection?
Please, I want from you to draw this result of the graph and send me in the comments below and order
to check it.
And in order to check that you understand the graph completely.
Now we apply the critical algorithm in order to find the shortest path and print the result.
OK, so this is the Crisco algorithms.
And see now let's move to implement it in Java.
But I want from you to draw this graph on paint or one note or any other program and send me a copy
of your image of your graph.